Why do they always put braces on teenage girls
at the exact moment when they're most
self-conscious about their appearance?
I don't know
Tom
I see him
Tom! Jesus!
Tom!
Hello, Amy
Hi, Darryl
Amy, would you tell the kids you'll be right back
And, shut the door and step outside...
talk to us for a minute
Okay
Be right back, you guys!
You're not supposed to go out, Amy
She's going to smoke a cigarette
Rudy, come on, I'm really late! Come on
How was school?
Stupid
Why do you say that?
We're supposed to write a story
for English homework. But they didn't tell us
what it's supposed to be about
What do you mean?
I mean, they didn't tell us what it's supposed
to be about. They said do whatever you want
Well, what's wrong with that?
I don't know, I just think it's unstructured
Well I'm sure you'll think of something
If you can't, I'll help you
Okay, here... Don't forget your backpack
It's not a backpack, it's a knapsack
Then don't forget the knapsack
Hey, Give me a hug. Okay
Guess who's been asking for you?
Oh no, really? Is that his car?
Oh yeah
Yeah, come in
Mister Everett
Oh yeah, Brian
Brian, hi. I'm Samantha Ann Prescott
I'm the lending officer
Yeah, hi. Hi. How are you. Have a seat
I am so sorry I was late
Yeah, we missed you before...
I got held up...
Believe me, it's nothing I make a habit of
I'm sure it's not
Actually, would you get that door for me, please
So I always run out at 3:15 to meet him...
then run real quick over to the sitters house
Anyway, Larry never seemed
to mind about it, so I was...
just hoping you'd feel the same way about it too
Well, Samantha, I realize that Scotsville...
is not exactly a major banking center
No, it's not
No, I know it's not
But it's kind of a personal challenge to me to see
what we can do to bring local service up to
the kinds of standards that we'd try to meet
if we were the biggest branch in the state
Now, that means I don't want anybody
running out at 3:15 or 3:30 or whenever
the bus happens to come in that day
So is there anybody else who can
pick up your son after school?
Does your husband work in the area?
Ahh, no. Rudy Sr. Isn't on the scene
so to speak
Well, I can give you a few days
to make some other arrangements. But...
Well, Brian...
I understand what you're saying
and I think it's great. I do
Because there's a lot of things around here
that could use some attention. Believe me
But I've been meeting this bus
every day for 3 years now
And it really does, it takes 15 minutes
And if I take the time out of my lunch hour...
Well, I'd prefer if you would
make some other arrangements, Okay?
I'll do my best
So, how old's your son?
He's eight
That's a terrific age
You got a letter from Uncle Terry
What?
What room is he going to stay in?
He can stay in the little room
You know what, he's not going to live here
He's only coming here, to stay for a little while
And it's okay if you don't remember
him because
you were only six the last time he was here
But I think it'll be nice
if you got a chance to know each other
Don't you think?
Rudy, would it distract you
if I put on some music?
No
Did you think of a story?
Uh-huh
What's it about?
My father
What... What about your father?
It's just a made-up story about him
Can I read it when you're done?
It's not very good
Don't say that
Anyway, Bob, it's kind of this adventure story
Rudy's father is a secret agent...
or something, working for the government
And it made me feel kinda weird. Because
I've never said much to him about Rudy Sr
Because I don't know what to say
And I don't know if I should just let him...
imagine what he wants to imagine
Of if I should sit him down sometime
and you know, tell him...
that his father's not such a nice person
Well I don't know, Sammy
what have you told him already
Not much. He knows...
He knows I don't have the highest opinion
of him
He knows I don't want to see him
That I don't want to know anything about him
Or to have anything to do with him
But I've tired to keep it kinda neutral
Well anyway, I could go
into a lot more detail, believe me
It's an interesting problem
I don't really know what to tell you
It's a little outside my personal field of expertise
Alright
I'd be glad to give it some thought
Okay
What?
No, nothing, I'm just glad to see you
I'm glad you called me
I bet you were surprised
Yeah, a little
I should get going
Really?
Yeah, I've got the babysitter
But, thanks for a lovely evening
Oh, thank you
Hey
Hey, Terry
Where'd you get that hat?
Got it on the street for a dollar
It's nice
Well it's pretty much your standard woolen hat
I had a very similar reaction to it
Umm... Umm...
Can I get that money from you?
Yeah, sorry
That all you have?
Yeah
Can you borrow some more from your brother?
That would involve speaking to him
Well I'm definitely gonna be gone
for a couple of days, Sheila
Why do you have to stay for so long?
Because my sister's not a bank, okay?
I can't just show up...
You think my brother's a bank!
Can we just cut the puerile crap!
I'll be back as soon as I can, okay!
I'm not the kind of guy everyone says I am
I know you're not
Okay, ahh... I'll call you tonight
Don't you want to tell me that you love me?
I love you
That was really convincing
Well, after this is over I think you should
seriously consider moving back home
Yeah
Alright
So you gonna call me tonight?
Definitely
Hello? Terry!
Whoa... Terry...
That's me
How's it going?
Going good...
Give me a hug
How you doing, good to see you
You too
Where you been?
Man I've been all over the place
Where you headed?
Just going up to see Sammy
Yeah, yeah. So she said you've been to Alaska?
Oh hi, how you going Mr. Parker
Good to see you again. Take care
So you working?
Yeah, yeah
Got a postcard every once in a while
Yeah, kinda been all over
Good to have you back here
Thanks, Darryl. You keep enforcing the peace
It'll be a little harder now that you're here
but I'll do what I can
No man, I'm just visiting
Hey, I'll see you around
Don't be a stranger, alright
Sorry about yesterday
I don't care
I was studying the bus description
And I got on the wrong bus
I missed my stop
I don't care, Terry. I'm so glad to see you
I'm glad to see you too, Sammy
So you're coming from work
No, it's Saturday
Yeah, no, it's just that you dressed so formally
Oh, no, you know, I thought I'd...
I thought it was special occasion. Which it is
No, it's good, it's good
I thought I'd get dressed up too
It's okay. You look fine
Yeah, this is the haute cuisine of garments
What?
Nothing. Nothing. So how are you?
We're fine, Terry
So, how's Rudy?
How are you?
Yeah...
Where have you been lately, Terry?
I know, I haven't been...
I got a postcard from you, from Alaska
Yeah, yeah I was up there for a little while
That was in the fall, Terry
Yeah I know, I've been out of touch
I was a little worried
I've been a lot of different places. I was down
in Florida for a little while
I was doing some work
in Orlando. I've been all over the place
Well I just wish
you had just let me know you were okay
Yeah, I just didn't realize it had been so long
You staying in town for a little while
Well I don't know
I got all these things
I got to do back in Worcester
Oh
Yeah, so I'm probably not gonna
be able to stay more than a day or so
Oh...
I'm kind of trying to keep to a schedule of sorts
Oh, that's alright
It's a long story and I don't want
to trouble you with it right now
Are you expecting someone?
Who would I be expecting here?
You just keep looking around, that's all
No, I was just wondering if we could
get some more refreshments, that's all
I actually got to confess to you, Sammy
That's the reason
you may not have heard from me for while
is I've been unable to write on the account
of that
I was in jail for a little while
You were what?
I sort of did a little time, I guess
down in Florida, it was just bullshit
What?
It was bullshit!
What did you do?
I didn't do anything! Maybe I was wronged?
No! Could I please... Oh my god!
Please let me tell you what happened
What happened?
I got into a fight in a bar in Florida
I was not the one who started it
But they worked up all this bullshit against me...
and they threw me in the pen for 3 months
I didn't write you because...
I didn't want you to get all upset about it
I thought, you would figure that
I was on the road for a while
It was stupid, I'm sorry
I didn't mean to make you worry
But you know what. I can't run around
doing stuff for not doing stuff
because it'll make you worry
Because I come back here
and tell you my fuckin' traumas
and I get this wounded
I've let you down, bullshit. Over and over again
It just cramps me
I just wanna get out from under it
And now I'm back in this fucking hole
explaining myself to you again!
Please stop cursing at me
I mean, I realize I'm in no position
to basically say anything
but it's not like I'm down there
in some redneck bar in Florida
having an argument with some stripper's
boyfriend
and I suddenly say to myself, hey
this would be
a good time to really stick it to Sammy
and get myself locked up for a few months
You don't write me for 6 months
I don't know where you are
I don't know if you're alive or dead
Then you show up out of nowhere
and you tell me you were in jail!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, Sammy
I'm really sorry
Sammy...
What?
I'm in the midst of a slight predicament
What do you need, money?
Um, yeah. I'm broke
I gotta get back to Worcester tomorrow
I got this girl there
and she's kind of in a bad situation
So... I just need to borrow some money
Whatever you can spare
I'll pay you back, man
I'll pay you back
I just...
I really wish mom was here
So do I, man
No one knows what to do with you
I know how they feel, man
Terry, can I ask you a question?
Sure
I mean, do you ever go to church anymore?
Sammy can we not talk about that shit?
Do you?
No, Sammy. I don't
Can you tell me why not?
Yeah, because I think it's ridiculous
Well, can you tell me without denigrating it?
It's primitive, okay, it's a fairy tale
Well have you ever considered maybe that's
what's making things so difficult for you?
No
That you've lost hold...
not just your religious feeling
but lost hold of any kind of anchor
Any kind of trust in anything
No wonder you drift around so much
I mean...
what's to stop you. How would you ever know
if you ever found the right thing
I'm not looking for anything, man
I'm just trying to get on with it
Here we go
Thank you
Thanks, Sammy
I'm really going to pay you back
Where we going?
Pick up Rudy
Well, do you even want me to visit now?
Because I can catch the bus at five o'clock
if that's what you want
Of course I want you to visit, you idiot!
I've been looking forward
to seeing you more than anything
I've told everybody I know that
you were coming home
I cleaned the whole fucking house
so it would look nice for you
I thought you'd stay at least a few days...
I had no idea that you were just broke again!
I just wish you'd send me an invoice!
Hi, is that, is that Malcom? Hi...
this is Terry Prescott
I've been trying to get a hold of Sheila...
and the phone isn't picking up
And I was wondering if...
She what?
Well is she alright?
Can I talk to her, please?
Okay, could you please give her a message
And tell that I...
That girl I'm with tried to kill herself
What?
She tired to kill herself
You have everything you need?
I think so
What are you going to do?
I don't know. Send her the money I guess
Maybe you should stay home for a while
Yeah, maybe a good idea
This 15 year old says
she's sick of her brother trying to control her
Dropped out of school, she's doing drugs
says there's nothing he can do about it
I'm going to bed
You have everything you need?
Ahh, yeah, thanks
Goodnight
Terry, I'm really glad you're home
Yeah me too, Sammy
So we'll drop Rudy off at the bus, then all
you have to do is drop me off at the bank...
and then pick Rudy up at 3:30
and drive him over to Carol's house
And that's it, she lives on Harvey Lane
Okay
Rudy knows where she lives
God, Mabel, don't those colors hurt your eyes?
Oh no, keeps me fresh
Yeah?
Hi Sammy, what can I do for ya'?
Umm, Brian, did you want us
to hand these time sheets...
in at the end of the day or
at the end of the week?
Oh, yeah. The end of the day will be fine
Just seems like an awful lot of extra paperwork
I like paperwork
You showed up
Looks that way
Put on your seatbelt
It pushes on my neck
What?
It pushes on my neck, it's uncomfortable
Well, when somebody slams into us
and you go sailin' through the windshield
that's liable to be uncomfortable too
Now put on your seatbelt
Mom's parents died in a car accident
Yeah, I know. They were my parents too
They are?
Yeah, your mom's my sister
Yeah, I know
So that means we have the same parents
Oh yeah
Umm, Carol just called
She said Terry and Rudy
never showed up at her house
You've got to be kidding
It's supposed to filed by number
the account number, not alphabetically
Sammy? Sammy!
Hey. Look, if you hold it further down, you're
gonna get a lot more power
You should be able
to hit that nail in with two or three hits. Look
See? Go ahead, try it
That's not the way I hold it
Well they way you hold it, is wrong
Why can't I just hold it my own way
You can...
Alright, good, that's good
Sammy, please see me, ASAP!!! Brian
Brian, did you want to see me?
Yeah, I was kinda wondering
what happened to you today
Didn't Mabel tell you
I had a false alarm about my son
Yeah well I kind of thought
you were gonna work that out?
I did work it out. More or less
Then what are you doing
leaving here in the middle of the day
Without so much
as a word of explanation to me, Sammy
Brian, don't yell at me...
I'm not yelling at you
I'm just... getting a little frustrated here
Well...
Sorry, would you close the door, please
And Eddie Dwyer lives in Buffalo, with his wife
and two kids, if you can believe it
That's depressing
Why?
I just never expected him the marrying type
Who are you talking about?
Some wild kids we use to know
Were you a wild kid?
Not as wild as your mom
Yeah, right
You don't believe me? No
Ask her
Mom, were you?
No comment
What are you doing?
Oh... Just reading some of your compositions
Why are you smoking?
Uhh, because it's bad. Don't ever do it
I won't
You know this used to be my room?
Yeah
Do you want it back?
No
Did you fight in Vietnam?
No. I wasn't even born yet
Were you ever in the Army?
No
My father was in the Army
I know
Unfortunately he didn't fight in Vietnam either
Were you friends with him?
Not really, I mean
we had some friends in common I guess...
I didn't like him very much
Why not?
Well... He wasn't very likeable
Why do you say that?
I don't know
he was always better than you at everything
Like if you were all playing basketball or
something, everybody's have like a friendly game
he was ready to kill somebody
if his team didn't win
Or if you told a joke or a story
he always had to tell a better one
Kinda gets annoying after awhile
Plus it was pretty scummy
how he split on you and your mom
He was a prick. Probably still a prick
Fortunately for you though
your mom is like the greatest
So you had some bad luck
and some good luck
You mind if I ask you a personal question?
I don't know
Do you like it here? I mean, in Scotsville
Yeah
Why?
I don't know...
My friends are here, I like the scenery
I don't know
I know... It's so... There's nothing to do here
Yes there is
No there isn't man, it's narrow. It's dull
It's a dull
narrow town full of dull narrow people
who don't know anything except
what things are like right around here
They have no perspective whatsoever
No scope
They might as well be living in the
19th century...
because they have no idea of
what's going on...
and if you try to tell 'em that
they wanna fuckin' kill you
What are you talking about?
I have no idea
you're a good kid
Sammy, please see me... Brian
Yeah, this doesn't apply to you
Sammy, but...
I've noticed that some of the employees
are setting their PC monitors...
to all kinds of crazy colors
Purple, polks dots...
what have you
And it's no big deal, but really...
this is a bank. You know?
It's really not appropriate
So I'm just asking that
people use the more quote unquote...
normal range of colors in the future
Like I said, this doesn't really apply to you
No. My computer palette's pretty conservative
Bob Steegerson
What are you wearing?
Mom?
What's up?
Do you know you have an enormous leak
coming from the upstairs hallway?
Yeah, I did
You guys sure you're going to be okay?
Yes. Yes
What is happening here?
It's just the problem is, the pipe is corroded
the whole length of the hall
So every time I put in a new piece
it starts leaking further down
Why don't I just call the plumber?
Why? He's not gonna do anything
different than what I'm doing
Yeah, we're making it worse
No we're not. Shut up...
Thanks. Thank you
So call if there's any problems
and if I'm not there. I'm either
on my way back home or on my way
Okay
Nice to meet you, Bob
You too
So lights out at ten
and don't spend the whole night watching TV
What's your idea of the whole night?
2 hours, tops
This kid is a sure bet to lead the way
for the next generation of California Surfers
What's your feeling about Bob?
I don't really know him that well
I have bad news for you
No...
Great. What are we supposed to do now?
Do you know how to play pool?
I've played it
I don't think they let kids in here. What?
I don't think they let kids in here
Well, we're not allowed to watch any more TV
so it's this or nothing
But if we get into trouble
let me do the talking. Okay?
Okay
I got a hundred bucks here says
me and my nephew can beat anybody in here
Only we gotta get the next game
because he's gotta be in bed by 10 o'clock
Just hit it nice and soft, nice and soft
One, two, three
Sorry
God damn it, Rudy
I thought you said you could play
Boys, it's all over but the cryin'
Bob, are you serious?
Yeah
I don't know what to say...
Look... I mean... I know that umm...
I haven't been the most...
decisive guy in the past
But, I don't know. I am tired of fooling around
And I love you
I... I'm totally... I don't know what to say
You could say yes...
or you could think about it some more
Would you like to think about it?
I want to think about it
Okay. Alright, fair enough
It's all yours, baby
Just make sure to hit it really gentle. But firm
And hit it a little low so you get some back spin
Okay. Don't even hit it, just kiss it
What do you mean, kiss it?
I mean tap it
Firm but very, very softly
And don't take the shot until you know
you're going to make it. Okay?
Okay
Let's go! Go! Go! Go...
What is going on here?
We were out doing some stargazing
and Rudy lost track of time
I totally warned him about it
You are a bad kid...
Hey, I think it's okay
just don't tell her where we went
Because she'll be really mad at me. Okay?
I won't
Hey, I mean it, Rudy, I'm not kidding
Did you know mom used to take me and Uncle
Terry out at night to look at the constellations?
Yeah
Did you see that one, what's the one...
It looks like a big W...
Cassiopeia
Yeah
Oww! Shit!
I've got a great idea...
What's that?
Why don't I call the plumber
Do whatever you want
Oh, what? What? That makes you mad?
No
Sorry
Brian, get off my ass
Excuse me?
I did not change the colors
on your stupid computer screen
Well then that's all you got to say!
There's nothing wrong with the work I do here
I didn't say there was
I've been doing fine the whole time
before you got here
And if you think that riding people in this pretty
ridiculous way is the way to improve service...
in this bank or anywhere else
you're out of your mind
May I respond?
No, that's all I really have to...
First of all, I would appreciate it
if you would not speak to me that way
I don't talk to you that way
and I would appreciate it...
if you did not talk to me that way
And second of all
if you tell me that you did not change my screen...
then of course I accept your answer
But you and I are going to have to
work together
And it's not going to happen with the attitude
with the lateness...
I do not have an attitude
You're fighting me every step of the way!
Okay, not you, you're not late
Well then don't say I'm late, if I'm not late
I would like to finish
Okay, you're all set
Dave, this is my wife, Nancy
Mabel, this is my wife, Nancy. Mabel...
Hi Nice to meet you
And Chuck...
Hi, nice to meet you. Nice to meet you
This is Sammy, our lending officer
Sammy this is my wife, Nancy
Hi, it's nice to meet you
Brian, I gotta sit down
Yeah. Sure, let's go in my office
I'm fine!
Brian? Yeah?
Mom
Rudy!
Look, I am really glad
you guys are getting along so well
like you have no idea but
if I can't rely on you...
to remember to get him once a day...
You can!
You took him to play pool
in the middle of the night...
and then telling him to lie to me about it!
I don't know
Get out of the car
What are we doing?
You're going to Carol's and I'm going home
Why can't I come with you
Because if you're such a baby
that you gotta tell your mommy...
about us playin' pool when I asked you not to
And I gotta listen to her shit all day...
then you're going to the babysitter's
so you can stay at the baby house
But I didn't...
You know what? Don't even fuckin' talk to me
I didn't!
Get out
You're working late
How did your wife like the bank?
Oh fine. She wasn't feeling so great
That's too bad
Oh no, I don't mean... She's not ill
She's just... I don't know
Pregnant
Yeah, that's right. She's pregnant
Well it can make you kind of cranky
Yeah
Look, I'm sorry we've been
stepping on each other's toes
Yeah, so am I
I'm really not that bad of a guy
I know you're not, Brian
But you're driving everybody crazy
Well, I'm trying to do my best here...
and I'm getting it from all sides
I know you are
Anyway, we'll work it out
Well, I could use a beer
I could use a tranquilizer
Last I heard, Rudy's Dad was living over
in Auburn. But that was a year ago
Must be so tough trying to raise a kid
on your own
I'm not sure but I think my wife
It's just hormones
Well, no, it isn't. But never mind
Thanks. Thank you...
Well, here's to improved
employee-management relations
Amen
You know you can't judge all of Scotsville
by the people in that bank, believe me
Well umm, let's... let's not talk about the bank
Okay
Let's just forget about the bank for tonight
Good idea
Sammy? Sammy!
Yeah?
I want you to tell me who changed
the colors on my computer screen
I'll never tell
Bob called
Where were you?
Nowhere, I had dinner with my boss
Kind of a late dinner, isn't it?
Yeah
How was Rudy?
Fine, he's asleep
Did the plumber come?
Yeah the fucking plumber came, geez...
Terry, just give me a break
What's the matter with you?
Nothing! I'm just tired
Want to smoke some pot?
No, I don't. Why, you got some?
So... Bob asked me to marry him
What are you going to do?
I don't know
if he'd asked me this same time last year...
I probably would have said yes
But the minute he asked me...
it was like someone was trying to strangle me
Whoa, bad sign
Yeah, I know. Plus, Terry, I fucked my boss...
What?
I know, and his wife is six months pregnant
Jesus Christ, Sammy
I know. I know
I'm sorry I got so ma at you before
I just don't want him...
you know, terrified of telling...
Well, that's not real his problem, Sammy
Oh? What do you think his problem is?
I think his problem is, he's totally sheltered...
you treat the kid like's three, instead of eight
So that's how he behaves
And how do you think he should behave?
I think he shouldn't have to run and
tell mommy...
every time he does something
she might not approve of, for one thing
Uh-huh
I mean, I took him to play pool
It was a little clandestine thing we did for fun
It wasn't a big secret, I mean, you care
I was actually trying to be nice to him
but he's so freaked out...
that he disobeyed your orders
that he has to fuckin' squeal on me...
and then I got to listen to your shit all-day
And I didn't fucking do anything
Okay, first of all, he didn't say anything
Darryl did. Okay?
Second, I don't give a shit
if you took him out to play pool
I was mad 'cause you left him
at the bus stop in the rain
No, I don't want you telling him not to squeal
Because I don't want him put in that position
Well that, is a perfect example
of what I'm talking about
You are an idiot
So what are you saying? Darryl told you?
Yes!
Sammy, please see me
Good morning
Yeah, good morning
Could you shut the door please
Brian, I just wanted to...
Brian...
You're awfully quiet
I'm sorry
So have you thought at all about what I said?
Sure, I've been thinking about it
So, any decisions, or...
Do you want to think about it some more?
Well I mean, I don't know, Bob
It's not like we've been going steady for
the last few months. You know what I mean?
Yeah, no... I know...
And then we see each other twice
and you suddenly say you want to get married?
No, you know, you're right
So what are you talking about
I don't know... I umm...
Last year, I thought that maybe you were
possibly
interested in that idea but I was the one...
who was ready at that point
So that's why I thought things slow down
with us
Don't make me feel bad for you
I don't want you to feel bad for me
It's Brian
Brian, where are you?
I'm buying milk, I just thought I'd say hello
Look, I know it's probably too late, but is there
any way you can come out for a little while?
Brian, I think you're going crazy
I know I am. Can you meet me?
Umm, okay
Umm, I have to go out for a little while
do you want anything?
Like what?
I don't know
Where are you going?
Yeah, where you going?
I have to go out for a little while
Where? Yeah, where?
I'm going to Mabel's house
Why?
You know what, Rudy? It's personal
It's a personal matter
That has to do with Mabel
And I just have to go
see her for a little while
Listen. Listen
I'm sorry I said you squealed on me
I was totally out of line...
and I really owe you an apology
Did you hear me?
I don't care
What's on your mind, Sammy?
Well, a lot. But principally...
I was just wondering if you had an opinion
If you know someone, in your family
or even just someone you really care about...
and they just can't quite get a hold of
themselves
So, guess who these are for?
Me!
That's right, my little friend
Hello, we're going fishing
I got a new rod and reel, five lures...
a hat, a knife and a fish scalier
That's great, sweetie
I'll get it
Well, I'm not really sure why you're here, Ron
I know I haven't been the model citizen
since I got here
But considering how things have been
going for me lately...
I thought I was doing pretty well
And I also find it kind of discouraging
that you seem to think that I'm...
in need of some kind of spiritual guidance
or what have you. So much so
that you're willing to disregard the fact that
I don't believe in any of this stuff at all
Well I didn't mean to discourage you
I mean it's really kind of insulting
Can I say something here?
Sammy asked me to come and talk to you
because it's her opinion that
you're not gonna find what you're looking for
the way you're looking for it
How would she know?
I'm really not here to try to get you to do
anything, or to get you to believe anything
And I'll tell you the same thing I told her
Which is, as far as I'm concerned
the only way she can help you...
is by her example
By trying to be a model for you
In the way she lives her life
And that doesn't mean she's supposed to be
a saint, either if that's what you're smiling about
I didn't realize I was smiling
You know, Terry, a lot of people come to
see me with all kinds of problems
Drugs, alcohol, marital problems
sexual problems
Good job you have, man
Well... I like it
Because even in this little town,
I really feel like
what I do is very connected with
the real center of people's lives
I'm not saying I'm always Mr Effective...
but I don't feel like my life is off
to the side of what's important
I don't feel that my happiness and comfort
are based on closing my eyes to trouble...
within myself or trouble in other people
I don't feel like a negligible little scrap...
floating around in some kind of empty void
With no sense of connected-ness to anything...
around me except by virtue of whatever little
philosophies I can scrape together on my own
Well...
Can I ask you, Terry... do you think
your life is important?
You mean, like, me personally?
My individual life?
Yeah
I'm not really sure, what do you mean?
It's important to me, I guess
And like, to my... you know
the people who care about me
But do you think it's important?
I...
Do you think it's important in the scheme
of things?
Not just because it's yours
or because you're somebody's brother
Because I really don't get
the impression that you do
Well I particularly don't think anybody's life
has any particular importance besides whatever
you know, like whatever we arbitrarily give it
Which is fine. I mean, you know
we might as well
I think my life is as important as anybody else
I don't know... A lot of what you're saying
has real appeal to me
A lot of the stuff they told us when we
were kids
But I don't want to believe or not believe
in something because I might feel bad
I want to believe in it and not believe in it
because I think it's true or not
Yeha, I want to think my life is important
That it's connected to something important
Well isn't there any way for you to believe
that without calling it God or
religion or whatever term it is that you
object to?
Yeah, I believe that
So Sammy, what example
are you setting for us tonight?
What time are we getting up to go fishing?
We're not going fishing
What do you mean?
Why not?
I think you should go fishing with Father Ron
I don't want to go fishing with Father Ron
Well, I'm not gonna take you
I'll take you sweetie
I realize that you're mad at me...
I'm not mad at you
but he didn't do anything to you
And you cannot promise a little boy
that you're gonna...
I just, you know, after all that
religions conversation, I realize...
it's probably not so good for him to be
spending so much time with someone...
who doesn't believe that his life is important
in the scheme of things
Would you please...
I'm serious
Listen. I am sure if you put your mind to it...
you can think of some other way
of getting back at me besides this
So would you please just give it some thought
and take him fishing tomorrow?
I would, Sammy, but I really don't think
it's good for him
You suck
You know my wife, Nancy
Yes, hello
Nice to see you
Father, nice sermon
Anyway, I don't know what the churches...
specific position is on fornication
and adultery these days
But I felt really hypocritical not saying
anything to you about it before, so...
what is the official position these days?
Well... It's a sin
Good. I think it should be
But we try not to focus on that aspect
of it, too much, right off the bat
Why not?
Well I think you should
Maybe it was better when you came in here
and they screamed at you for having sex
with your married boss
They told you what a terrible thing it was
They were really mean to you
Maybe it'd be better if you told me
I was endangering my immortal soul
And that if I don't quit...
I'm going to burn in hell
Don't you ever think that?
Umm... no
Well it would be a lot better than all this...
why do you think you're in this situation...
psychological bullshit you hear all the time
Well, why do you think you're in this situation?
With which one?
All of them?
I feel sorry for them
Isn't that ridiculous?
I've never been so bored in my whole life
We should have been here around 7 or 8 AM
What time is it now?
02:30
Was my father a good fisherman?
Yeah, he was good at all that stuff
He knew every
thing about the woods
everything about hunting
everything about fishing, everything about cars
If he wasn't such a pain in the ass
he would've been a lot of fun to be around
Maybe he's nice now?
I doubt it
Well, I think he is
How would you know?
Did you ever meet him?
No
Were you ever curious about meeting him?
I guess so
He lives near here
I thought he lived in Alaska
No... I lived in Alaska
He lives in Auburn, as far as I know
We could look him up in the phone book
Wanna try it?
Alright
But, Rudy...
I'm sure I don't have to tell you this
But I'm not kidding, man
Don't tell your mother
Can I get you something?
Hey, you want to go for a walk? Or a drive
it's really nice out
No, I'm not going to stay long
Bob, I don't wanna get married
Okay
I've been thinking about it for a while...
and if you had asked me last year
I'm sure I would have said yes
Oh, thank you
But I'm not sure it would have been
an good idea then either
I've been going through a really hard time lately
I think that getting engaged to you or
anybody else
would probably be the stupidest
most self destructive thing I could possibly do
Okay
And I really think you need to grow up
Well how about we fix
my personality some other time?
Okay
I really hope we can still be friends
Oh yes, me too...
Bob...
Bob... l...
I don't know... Sammy, I love you, I really...
I love you
I love you too
Oh shit, I got to go! I'm sorry
What? Where do you have to go?
I have to get Mabel her car
Now?
I don't understand, how are we leaving things?
I don't know. Call me later
This is incredible
That is not what I mean
Maybe we should call first?
Well we're right here
Come on
There he is
His last name is Kolinsky?
Yeah
Go ahead, knock
Yes?
Hi, we're looking for Rudy
Who should I say is calling?
An old friend
Who is it!
He says, an old friend!
How old is he?
Hey!
Hey, Rudy
Hey
Hi, I'm Terry
Hello
This is Rudy
You don't say
Rudy, meet Rudy
I'll just be in the kitchen
Nice meeting you
Okay if we come in for a minute?
What the hell are you doing?
What do you mean, what am I doing?
Could you back away from the door please?
We just wanna come in...
Back away from the door please?
What are you doing here?
Just wanted the kid to see you, man
Well now he saw me
Now you saw me, alright?
Now, do you mind?
Man you are really...
I'm trying to be polite, alright
So just take off, okay, just take off
I just wanna...
Do you know what you're doing here?
Just get out of here, alright
You know what, man
you're still a fucking asshole
I'm an asshole? Get out of here!
Get your fucking hands off him!
Get off!
Listen, Officer. I just came down here
to talk to the guy and he starts shoving me
And you're not the boy's legal guardian?
I don't even know if that's my kid
You're a fucking lying piece of shit!
Then they were fighting
He's on our property...
I don't know who this guy is
You know you came here...
We have a right to protect ourselves
I came here to talk to him...
Step back
He started the whole thing
and now I'm being arrested
Stop talking
What's going to happen to him?
Terry, stop talking
Alright...
Any idea where we might be able
to contact his mother?
No, because he's not my Goddamn kid!
Oh my gosh...
What's the matter?
Oh my gosh, what time is it?
Oh my God, oh my God, it's nine-thirty!
Hey, you know Nancy's going to be gone
for the rest of the week
You know, Brian...
Yeah?
I don't mean to be... Couldn't we just...
I mean could we give it a rest?
Yeah, sure, if you want to
I mean, I just think, I don't know
we had a great little fling...
you know, why push it
Is that okay? I just...
Yeah, sure, okay. No, you're right
So we are still friends?
Sure
Alright...
Around two o'clock this afternoon
Yes, a '97 red Subaru Outback
New York plates, AUZ416. Please
Thanks for coming over
I want to have a car handy, just in case
No problem
Yes, what about other towns?
Yes. Yes
I called the Highway Patrol, four times!
What am I supposed to do all night?
Hello?
Anyone hear from Sammy this morning?
I didn't
Un-huh. Well, if anybody ever hears
from her again, would you let me know
Yes...
Thank you Mike, I'll give you a call
Alright
It's going to be alright
We got on the phone with Rudy Sr a little bit...
and he's calmed down
he wants to forget the whole thing
Darryl, I really appreciate this
Yeah, it's Brian
Brian...
What the hell happened to you today, lady?
You're fried! Good!
Rudy?
Yeah?
Is there anything you want to ask me
about your father?
Oh, that wasn't my father
What?
That wasn't him. I heard him tell the cops
No, Rudy, that was him
I wish it wasn't, but it was
No it wasn't
Yes, Rudy it was
Your father's name is Rudy Kolinsky
He lives in Auburn
Would you turn it off, please?
You don't have to say anything, Sammy
I want you to leave
What do you mean?
I mean, I don't think you should live here
I don't think you know how to behave
around an eight year old...
and I don't know how to make you stop
So I don't think you should live here
I don't know what else say
I don't know how to behave
around an eight year old...
That's right
I think you don't know how to behave
around an eight year old
Are you out of your mind?
Now you just listen to me
I may not be the greatest mother in the world
But I'm doing the best I know how
And he doesn't need you to rub his face in shit...
because you think it's good for him!
He's going to find out the world is a
horrible place
and that people suck soon enough
and without any help from you. Believe me!
I think you should get your own place
I thought, maybe...
I'd be happy to help you out financially
What do you mean, get my own place?
Yes. Yes
Why would I do that?
Why don't I just leave, period
If that's what you want to do, that's fine
But that's not what I'm saying
You are an important person to Rudy
And you are the most important person to me
But I'm saying I can't take anymore of this
Well...
And I thought you could sell
your half of the house to me
And then I could pay you back a certain
amount, whatever it is...
over a certain period of time
No, you know what, I'll just go
Well, that's not what I'm saying
Where you gonna go?
I don't know, I just want out of this town
And if you've got any sense
when you're older you'll leave too
You know your mom's going to stay
in this town for the rest of her life
You wanna know why?
Because she thinks she has to
She thinks there's all these things she has to do
I'll tell you one thing about your mom
She's a bigger fuck up than I ever was
I know I messed up, okay
You think I enjoy getting thrown in jail?
Because I wanted you to face that prick
your Dad, like a little man
And show you what kind of guy he is?
I got carried away, I know...
I lost my temper, just a little bit...
Which is not the end of the world either
by the way, just for future reference
And now she's throwing me out of
my own home
because, I fucked up a little bit
Which I totally admit...
I was like, totally ready to admit that
I could go with you
Well thanks man, but I ahh...
I can't really take care of you
Is that for you?
Yeah, I'm just gonna stay at Ray's until I leave
Well, you don't have to do that
Yeah, well, that's what I wanna do
Well... Are you gonna come back
and say goodbye?
No, I'm just gonna take off, I'll see ya'
Look, I know you're upset about
Uncle Terry leaving
and so am I
But he's not in control of himself
And I don't want him hurting your feelings
anymore or mine
And you may not like it but that's
how it's going to be. Okay?
I don't care
You don't care? I don't care either
Well I'm sorry you're having all this trouble
Thank you
You made a pretty good speech to me
the other day about people...
sticking to their commitments. Yeah
Well you made a commitment Sammy
to this bank, to this job
I know I did
And to work things out with this tough new
son of a bitch boss of yours
How whatever may have passed
between us after hours...
doesn't mean you can walk away
from that commitment
Yeah, even if you have a
legitimate family emergency
I'm really sorry I didn't call in...
That is why I think
in the calm cold light of day...
that you and I have to both think real hard...
about whether you really want to continue
on here at Outpost Bankers Trust
You've got to be kidding
You're not happy, I'm not happy
and it's not good for you...
and it's sure as heck not good for the bank
You know, you're the worst manager
we've ever had
Come on, Sammy...
By far, the worst
I don't want to trade insults with you
Well I don't want to be fired
Brian. I've been here for 7 years
And if I were you
I'd be a little nervous about firing an employee...
I just had an affair with. Okay
Don't threaten me...
I'm not threatening you
I just think it's an area we should explore
You explore it, I'm going back to work
Oh, and I have to pick up Rudy today
because there's no one else who can do it
I'll find someone else when I have time
Yeah fine
Why don't you just take over the whole bank
Well, I called Uncle Terry
where he said he'd be staying...
and there was no answer
So I don't know if he's still in town
Rudy, you're not speaking to me?
Well, I'm sorry you're mad at me
but I only did what I had to do
I just hope you don't stay mad at me
for the rest of your life
Rudy, that's enough
Rudy!
Now you got to cut this out!
What did I do?
You don't know what you're talking about!
There was nothing else I could do!
I don't know how to explain it to you
any better than that, but...
you cannot go on this way
because you don't know anything about it...
and you don't know what you're doing!
Okay, I'm sorry!
I don't want you to be sorry
I want you to stop it!
I'm stopping
See, I'm stopping. I'm stopping
Ray's house
I didn't know if you'd left yet
No, I'm leaving tomorrow
What time?
Umm, bus leaves at 9
Well, I'd really like to see you before you go
I mean, can I give you a lift
do you want to have breakfast or anything
I think Rudy, would really like to say goodbye
Yeah, I don't know, I mean...
Terry, you can't just leave like this
Alright, alright, I'll come by tomorrow morning
Alright, but just...
we have to be out of the house by 8 o'clock
so I don't want to tell Rudy you're coming...
unless you think you can make it
no... I'll be there
Alright
You better get your sneakers on
Sweetie, I'm sorry, but we have to go
Why can't I miss school one day?
Hey, how's it going, man
Sorry I'm late
So Rudy, if I write you a letter
will you write me back?
Yeah
That's gonna be pretty nice for you, because
I write a pretty Goddamn interesting letter
Yeah, we'll see
Well, alright, say goodbye
Bye
You need some cash for the bus?
No, I got a few bucks
aren't you gonna be late for work?
Oh, yeah... That's okay
Terry, I don't even know where you're going
Well, yeah... I don't really
have a concrete plan yet
I got to go back to Worcester and get my stuff
Oh, you're gonna try and see that girl?
Yeah, you know
I thought I'd try and show my face...
let her brother have a crack at me
What?
No...
I don't want anyone to have a crack at you
I'm just kidding. I just thought
I just thought I'd check up on her
And then after that, I don't know
I've been thinking about Alaska a lot
I still got a lot of friends out there
I don't really know
Anyway, I'll write you
You will?
Sure, Sammy. Of course I will, you know that
What is gonna happen to you?
Nothing too bad. But I gotta tell you, Sammy...
I know things didn't work out too well
this time...
but it's really good to know, wherever I am...
whatever stupid shit I'm doing
that you're back at my home, rooting for me
It's all going to be alright, Sammy
Comparatively, and I'll be back
around this way again
I just feel like I'm never going to see you again
Of course you will, you never have to
worry about that, ever
Don't go anywhere
until you know where you're going
I do, I do know where I'm going
I'm going back to Worcester
I'm going to try and see that girl
And then depending on what happens there
I'm going to see if there's work for me out west
And if there is, I'm going out there
this summer and make some money
And if there isn't, I'll figure something else out
Maybe I'll stay in the east. I don't know...
I really liked Alaska
It was really beautiful, and it just...
It made me feel good
And before things got so messed up...
I was doing pretty well out there
Seriously
But I couldn't stay here, Sammy
I don't wanna live here
But I'll keep in touch
And I will be back, because
I want to see you and I want to see Rudy
We'll have Christmas together, how's that?
We'll all have Christmas together
Come on, Sammy. You can trust me
Come on, Sammy, look at me... Look at me...
Sammy, remember when we were kids
Remember what we always
used to say to each other
Of course I do
Remember when we were kids
I'll really miss you